QUESTIONS = [
  {
    "question": "The kind of cost which are part of the cost of a product rather an expense of the period in which they are incurred are called",
    "options": {
      "A": "material cost",
      "B": "costing",
      "C": "product cost",
      "D": "direct labour"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The midway between the minimum stock level and the maximum stock is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "total cost",
      "B": "marginal",
      "C": "medium",
      "D": "average"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lowest level of stock that is established by management which is considered at a lead time and demand for materials is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "lead time",
      "B": "maximum",
      "C": "stock level",
      "D": "minimum"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of accounting for cost which begins with the recording of income and expenditure is refers to",
    "options": {
      "A": "management",
      "B": "production",
      "C": "auditing",
      "D": "cost accounting"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The measurement of Cost and value of people for the organization is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "human resource accounting",
      "B": "cost accounting",
      "C": "cost management",
      "D": "recruitment"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Those materials that become an integral part of the finished product, the cost of which are directly assigned to the specific physical units and charged to the prime cost are known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "indirect material",
      "B": "direct expenses",
      "C": "direct overheads",
      "D": "direct material"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The quantity of materials an organization will purchase at a time to enjoy economy of scale is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "demand",
      "B": "order place",
      "C": "economic order",
      "D": "carrying inward"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost of transforming direct materials into finished products excluding direct materials cost is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "mannual",
      "B": "conversion",
      "C": "target",
      "D": "progressiv"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The level of inventory at which it becomes necessary to place order for new supply is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "stocking",
      "B": "quantity",
      "C": "re-order",
      "D": "carrying"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Financial accounting provides information mostly at",
    "options": {
      "A": "quaterly",
      "B": "two years",
      "C": "monthly",
      "D": "yearly basis"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of cost accounting system capable of adapting itself to the changing situations of business is known as what",
    "options": {
      "A": "durable",
      "B": "simplicity",
      "C": "elasticity",
      "D": "adaptability"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ratio that measures the extent to which fixed interest liabilities relate to the equity is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "cash ratio",
      "B": "current ratio",
      "C": "gearing ratio",
      "D": "acid test ratio"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Centres that are engaged on production and other times on service works are called",
    "options": {
      "A": "cost pool",
      "B": "unit",
      "C": "mixed cost",
      "D": "design"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost which can be influenced by the action of specified member of an undertaking is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "normal cost",
      "B": "department",
      "C": "controllable cost",
      "D": "section"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The costs incurred on idle plant during business temporary close down are known",
    "options": {
      "A": "irrelevant cost",
      "B": "shutdown",
      "C": "relevant cost",
      "D": "future cost"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A situation where an old established standard designed principally to satisfy a given objective is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "absorption",
      "B": "job specifics",
      "C": "basic standard",
      "D": "quality assurance"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amount of time it takes for the material to be delivered from the supplier after an order has been placed is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "lead time",
      "B": "quantity order",
      "C": "unit order",
      "D": "order level"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process whereby the business assess whether the benefits and revenues of a proposed business is more than costs is known as what",
    "options": {
      "A": "cost management",
      "B": "cost-benefit-analysis",
      "C": "cost analysis",
      "D": "cost allocation"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost of searching for new products, new application of materials, or improved methods is refers to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "compound",
      "B": "basic",
      "C": "imperial",
      "D": "research"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost or expenditure which a firm incurs for producing or acquiring a good or service is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "labour cost",
      "B": "separate cost",
      "C": "material cost",
      "D": "actual cost"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many professional accounting bodies in Nigeria",
    "options": {
      "A": "1",
      "B": "3",
      "C": "2",
      "D": "4"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The kind of cost that means a location, person or item of equipment for which costs may be ascertained and used for the purpose of cost control is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "cost ascertainment",
      "B": "cost unit",
      "C": "cost centre",
      "D": "cost control"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The four areas that are related to forecasting are sales, production, earning and",
    "options": {
      "A": "record",
      "B": "allocation",
      "C": "determination",
      "D": "cost"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accounting system that recognizes price changes of commodity from time to time is refers to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "deflation",
      "B": "economy of scale",
      "C": "inflation",
      "D": "demand"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The kind of cost which cannot be influenced by the action of a specified member of an undertaking is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "controllable",
      "B": "uncontrollable",
      "C": "demand cost",
      "D": "irrelevant cost"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The essentials of cost accounting that apportioned indirect expenses to products, departments or jobs that must be fair and equitable is called the essentials of",
    "options": {
      "A": "reliable",
      "B": "timeliness",
      "C": "equity",
      "D": "accuracy"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The branch of accounting that centers on employees is refers to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "production",
      "B": "human resource",
      "C": "marketing",
      "D": "finance"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost that do not vary as output changes is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "variable cost",
      "B": "relevant cost",
      "C": "sunk cost",
      "D": "fixed cost"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Total cost is the combination of variable and",
    "options": {
      "A": "marginal cost",
      "B": "fixed cost",
      "C": "average cost",
      "D": "sunk cost"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost that do not change as the level of business activity changes are refers to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "explicit",
      "B": "production cost",
      "C": "implicit",
      "D": "sunk"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The quantity of materials an organization will purchase at a time to enjoy economy of scale is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "demand",
      "B": "economic order",
      "C": "order place",
      "D": "carrying inward"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of accounting for cost which begins with the recording of income and expenditure is refers to",
    "options": {
      "A": "production",
      "B": "cost accounting",
      "C": "auditing",
      "D": "management"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost which does not vary proportionately but simultaneously and does not remain stationary at all times is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "cost pool",
      "B": "semi-variable cost",
      "C": "variable cost",
      "D": "marginal cost"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of cost that do not involve cash outlay is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "relevant cost",
      "B": "future",
      "C": "imputed/hypothetical",
      "D": "variance"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "An additional stock held by an organization over and above the minimum stock is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "supply",
      "B": "order level",
      "C": "quantity demanded",
      "D": "buffer/ safety"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Financial accounting provides information mostly at",
    "options": {
      "A": "quaterly",
      "B": "monthly",
      "C": "two years",
      "D": "yearly basis"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The kind of cost which are part of the cost of a product rather an expense of the period in which they are incurred are called",
    "options": {
      "A": "costing",
      "B": "product cost",
      "C": "direct labour",
      "D": "material cost"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The level of inventory at which it becomes necessary to place order for new supply is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "quantity",
      "B": "stocking",
      "C": "re-order",
      "D": "carrying"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost of transforming direct materials into finished products excluding direct materials cost is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "progressive",
      "B": "target",
      "C": "conversion",
      "D": "mannual"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lowest level of stock that is established by management which is considered at a lead time and demand for materials is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "maximum",
      "B": "stock level",
      "C": "lead time",
      "D": "minimum"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Centres that are engaged on production and other times on service works are called",
    "options": {
      "A": "cost pool",
      "B": "unit",
      "C": "mixed cost",
      "D": "design"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "A situation where an old established standard designed principally to satisfy a given objective is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "absorption",
      "B": "job specifics",
      "C": "basic standard",
      "D": "quality assurance"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The amount of time it takes for the material to be delivered from the supplier after an order has been placed is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "unit order",
      "B": "order level",
      "C": "quantity order",
      "D": "lead time"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The charging of the apportioned cost centre overhead to cost units is referred to as ?",
    "options": {
      "A": "absorption cost",
      "B": "labour cost",
      "C": "apportionment",
      "D": "material cost"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost which can be influenced by the action of specified member of an undertaking is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "controllable cost",
      "B": "normal cost",
      "C": "department",
      "D": "section"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost or expenditure which a firm incurs for producing or acquiring a good or service is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "separate cost",
      "B": "actual cost",
      "C": "material cost",
      "D": "labour cost"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost of searching for new products, new application of materials, or improved methods is refers to as",
    "options": {
      "A": "imperial",
      "B": "basic",
      "C": "research",
      "D": "compound"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of cost accounting system capable of adapting itself to the changing situations of business is known as what",
    "options": {
      "A": "elasticity",
      "B": "durable",
      "C": "simplicity",
      "D": "adaptability"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ratio that measures the extent to which fixed interest liabilities relate to the equity is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "cash ratio",
      "B": "gearing ratio",
      "C": "acid test ratio",
      "D": "current ratio"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "The costs incurred on idle plant during business temporary close down are known",
    "options": {
      "A": "relevant cost",
      "B": "irrelevant cost",
      "C": "future cost",
      "D": "shutdown"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "MCQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "Financial accounting forms the basis for analysis and interpretation for furnishing meaningful data to the _______.",
    
    "answer": "management",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Direct costs are those which are directly identifiable with a unit of _______.",
    
    "answer": "operation",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main function of cost accounting is to disclose sources of _______ in process of production.",
    
    "answer": "wastage",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost data help management in determining future production _______.",
    
    "answer": "policy",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management accounting is just a _______.",
    
    "answer": "guide",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are seven branches of accounting: financial, cost, management, inflation, social, value-added, and _______.",
    
    "answer": "human resource accounting",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting serves as a guide to price fixing of _______.",
    
    "answer": "products",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Productive cost centres are those actually engaged in making _______.",
    
    "answer": "products",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cost centre is a location, person, or item of equipment for which costs may be ascertained and used for cost _______.",
    
    "answer": "control",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Semi-variable cost contains both a fixed-cost component and a _______ component.",
    
    "answer": "variable",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The three elements of cost are material, labour, and _______.",
    
    "answer": "expenses",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The system of cost accounting must provide for accuracy in terms of both cost ascertainment and _______.",
    
    "answer": "presentation",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Indirect expenses include repairs to machinery, insurance, lighting, and _______.",
    
    "answer": "rent",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Implicit costs are theoretical costs not recorded in the _______.",
    
    "answer": "books of accounts",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Chartered Institute of Management Accountants defines a cost unit as a unit of quantity of product, service, or _______.",
    
    "answer": "time",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting helps in determining selling price by providing the total cost of _______.",
    
    "answer": "production",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Standard cost is a predetermined calculation of how much costs should be under specific _______ conditions.",
    
    "answer": "working",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Financial accounting provides information only at the end of the _______.",
    
    "answer": "year",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Book costs do not involve any cash payments but provisions are made in the _______.",
    
    "answer": "books of accounts",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost may be classified into fixed cost, variable cost, and _______ cost.",
    
    "answer": "semi-fixed",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Indirect costs cannot be easily identified in relation to a plant, product, or _______.",
    
    "answer": "department",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting is a process of collecting, analyzing, summarizing and evaluating various alternative courses of _______.",
    
    "answer": "action",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "From a buyer\u2019s point of view, the cost of a product can be called the _______.",
    
    "answer": "price",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Statistical methods make information more impressive, comprehensive, and _______.",
    
    "answer": "intelligible",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting provides a base for management accounting whereas management accounting is derived from cost and _______ accounting.",
    
    "answer": "financial",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting system enables management to minimize _______ and losses.",
    
    "answer": "wastages",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management accounting is concerned with the provisions and use of accounting information to managers within _______.",
    
    "answer": "organizations",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management accounting helps in translating given objectives and strategies into specified goals for _______.",
    
    "answer": "attainment",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting is concerned with short-term planning while management accounting is concerned with short and _______ range planning.",
    
    "answer": "long",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Costing reports provide information about profitable or _______ areas of operation.",
    
    "answer": "unprofitable",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting helps management in making suitable _______ such as make or buy decisions.",
    
    "answer": "decisions",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In business and accounting, cost is the monetary value that a company has spent in order to produce _______.",
    
    "answer": "something",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Accounting has evolved to show various segments as pieces of knowledge that demand _______.",
    
    "answer": "attention",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost reduction and cost control programs minimize cost of production of goods and _______.",
    
    "answer": "services",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Human resource accounting is the measurement of the cost and value of _______ for the organization.",
    
    "answer": "people",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fixed costs do not vary with changing _______.",
    
    "answer": "output",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The three areas in which the scope of cost accounting could be classified are cost ascertainment, cost record, and _______.",
    
    "answer": "cost control",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost control is exercised at different stages in a factory such as acquisition of materials and deployment of _______.",
    
    "answer": "labour",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost accounting provides the detailed cost information that management needs to control current operations and plan for the _______.",
    
    "answer": "future",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management accounting provides a means of communicating management plans upward, downward, and _______.",
    
    "answer": "outward",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Inflation accounting recognizes that prices of a commodity change with time due to inflation and decline in purchasing power of _______.",
    
    "answer": "money",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Costing serves a number of purposes, among which the ascertainment of cost was considered the _______ objective.",
    
    "answer": "primary",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost accounting system should be capable of adapting itself to changing situations of _______.",
    
    "answer": "business",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explicit costs are those expenses actually paid by the _______.",
    
    "answer": "firm",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Service cost centres act as essential aids for the _______ centres.",
    
    "answer": "productive",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management accounting does not restrict itself to financial data but also uses _______ information.",
    
    "answer": "qualitative",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Discretionary fixed costs are those which are set at fixed amounts for specific _______.",
    
    "answer": "time periods",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Committed fixed costs arise from possession of plant, equipment, and basic _______.",
    
    "answer": "organization structure",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cost data helps management in formulating policies and making _______ decisions.",
    
    "answer": "business",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main aim of management accounting is to help management in its functions of planning, directing, controlling and _______.",
    
    "answer": "decision making",
    "type": "Fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Economic cost includes both actual direct costs and _______ cost.",
    
    "answer": "opportunity",
    "type": "Fill"
  }
]